Cameron McCawley

cameronismccawley@gmail.com | cameron-mccawley.github.io | linkedin.com/in/cameron-mccawley

Summary

Dependable and focused student with experience in applying both defensive and offensive security in a competitive environment. Significant experience in teaching as a learning assistant in CS classes. Currently studying cyber security and mathematics at Oregon State University.

Education

BS, Computer Science (Security) | Minor in Mathematics | Oregon State University | 3.93 GPA | Est. Graduation June 2023

- Key Courses: Intro to Databases, Analysis of Algorithms, Software Engineering I, Data structures, Web Development, Computer Architecture and Assembly, Numerical Analysis, Linear Algebra I, Vector Calculus, Infinite Series and Sequences
- Led a major UX design project focused on using collected empirical and analytical user data to create a high-fidelity prototype for a media server application
- Led a major web application project that used NodeJS and Handlebars in order to create a dynamic website that stored data using MariaDB

Skills

Security

- Reverse Engineering (Ghidra Decompiler, gdb)
- Binary Exploitation (pwntools)
- · Vulnerability Scanning (Nessus)
- · Network Security (Wireshark, nmap)
- Penetration Testing (Metasploit, Kali Linux tools)

Infrastructure

- Virtualization (VMware Workstation, VirtualBox)
- Cloud Computing (AWS, Azure)
- Containerization (Docker)
- Rapid Prototyping (Vagrant)

Programming

- C, C++
- Python
- HTML/CSS/JS/SQL
- x86 Assembly
- Git

Work Experience

Electrical Engineering & Computer Science Learning Assistant | Oregon State University | March 2020 - Current

- Held extended office hours helping students understand and learn difficult C++ concepts
- Ensured a smooth asynchronous experience when hosting Zoom labs
- Mastered the CS 161 and CS 162 material set in order to help students to the fullest
- Graded students' live code demos and design documents swiftly
- Gave live coding demos at the beginnings of labs as review of topics learned in lecture

Activities/Awards

OSU Security Club (2019 - Current)

- Active Club member from 2019-present
- Worked with our CTF team OSUSEC to bring us to the top five in many CTF competitions
- Participated in Cyber Defense Competitions to gain a better understanding of the blue team side of security
- Placed 2nd in our internal CTF competition and ended up writing over 20 unique challenge writeups

Cyber Threat Hunting Level 1 Cert, (2021)

- Attended Active Countermeasure's network threat hunting training course
- Analyzed packets with tools such as Zeek, tshark, datamash, and Rita to thwart command • and controls
- Networked with CISOs and security experts from around the country
- Learned methods for packet capturing to guarantee the best data for analysis

Recent Awards

- 26th place, DOE Cyberforce Competition 2020 (remote, individual)
- 1st place, BSides PDX CTF 2020 (remote, team)
- 5th place, Fireshell CTF 2020 (remote, team)
- 3rd place, NSA CC 2020 (remote, team)